

Bo Chipev

More than 10 years of experience in creating software solutions that put the user first.

Alkmaar, The Netherlands +31 6 41 36 56 59 bo.chipev@proton.me LinkedIn Website

Who am I?

A software development generalist with strong strategic and research skills, bridging the gap between design and technology. I thrive in complex, technical product environments, especially where the end user is a developer, engineer, or technical specialist.

What am I looking for?

A senior role within a mature (or maturing) product organization that includes mentorship and leadership responsibilities, ideally in DevUX or technical enterprise software.

Skills

Design: Concepting, Wireframing, Prototyping, Animations & Micro interactions, Design systems, Figma

Research: Usability testing, Interviewing, Surveying, A/B testing, Preference testing

Management: Growth mentorship, Planning & organization, Prioritization (RICE Model), OKRs, Agile, Scrum

Technical: Vanilla JS, Astro.js, CSS, Tailwind, SQL, APIs, Git, Docker

Soft: Stakeholder management, Critical thinking, Problem solving, Facilitation, Conflict resolution

Languages: English (C2), Dutch (C1), Bulgarian (Native)

Work experience

Senior UX researcher & user validation engineer @ tweakers.net (part of DPG Media)

2019 - present Amsterdam (hybrid)

Created user interfaces, flows, and interactions, grounded in extensive user research (surveys, interviews, forum analysis) for a product with 1.5M monthly active users.

Led end-to-end validation:

- Usability testing (moderated panels of 6, analysis & reporting).
- A/B testing (technical implementation and quantitative analysis).
- Beta testing (planning, execution, and synthesis of findings).

Facilitated design sprints, both in-brand and within the broader DPG Media organization.

Managed and developed design interns, overseeing day-to-day responsibilities and mentoring growth.

Chaired the ovearching organization's UX chapter, representing the design discipline in cross-brand discussions and acting as liaison to senior management.

UX designer @ Qelp, now Foundever

2017 - 2019 Amsterdam

Instituted a structured design process for customizing a white-label solution for technical support specialists. Established a robust, repeatable set of steps during the client design customizations projects.

Work experience (cont.)

Generalist @ Cupenya (Rockstart Web/Mobile Accelerator Startup)

2014 - 2017 Amsterdam

Joined as the first non-founding employee, contributing across design, marketing, and product in a fast-paced startup environment.

Technology & Science reporter @ capital.bg

2011 - 2012 Sofia, Bulgaria

Covered technology and science for Bulgaria's leading business newspaper and news site, building a strong foundation in software, business, and innovation trends.

Education

Design Thinking Certification

2023 Design Thinking Academy Amsterdam

User Experience Design & Resarch Certification

2018 - 2019 UX Academy, accredited by Caledonian University Glasgow

New Media & Digital Culture (Master's Degree)

2012 - 2014 University of Amsterdam

Journalism & Mass Communications (Bachelor's Degree)

2007 - 2011 American University in Bulgaria

Talks

A design system without a front-end framework?

A story of design systems, refactors, a designer writing code, darkmode and a few other spicy anecdotes. 2024 VGZ Headquarters, Arnhem

Strategic shift: Moving towards a vision-driven white label product

2018 Qelp, Amsterdam

Volunteering

Interactive Language Education for Children aged 3+

Developed an audio-visual experience as a web-application aimed at helping toddlers learn the letters of different alphabets and associate them with corresponding words. Built using Astro.js. Currently supporting Dutch, Lithuanian and Bulgarian.

2024 Website

Team Vrijwillig (Gemeente Alkmaar)

Helping on an ad-hoc basis with municipal activities and events.

2021 - Present